Finding Aid for the Alec Hyatt King Papers, 1859-1998
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
Alec Hyatt King Papers, 1859-1998
Mus. Arc. 35
King, A. Hyatt (Alec Hyatt), 1911-1994
14 boxes (450 folders)
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
The collection consists of printed materials and correspondence compiled by the noted British music librarian, bibliographer, and musicologist Alec Hyatt King. The printed materials include offprints of articles, complete journal issues, exhibition catalogs, catalogs from music publishers and booksellers, membership lists and organizational histories, and concert programs.
Administrative Information
Terms of Access
Materials can be examined by qualified researchers in the Music Library during hours of operation during which Music Librarians are present. In order to insure access, researchers are advised to contact the Music Library in advance of visits.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Alec Hyatt King's son, Edmund King, in 2002.
Accruals and Additions
No further accruals are expected to this collection.
Biographical Note
Alec Hyatt King (1911-1994) was a noted bibliographer, musicologist, and author of more than forty articles and books. He began his career at the British Museum at the age of twenty-three and continued his employment there until his retirement in 1977. He served as superintendent of the Music Room 1944-1958 and was named deputy keeper of the Department of Printed Books in the British Museum in 1959. His research specialties included Mozart, Handel, music printing, music sales catalogs, and music bibliography. King was also active in the fields of musicology and librarianship through his membership and participation in organizations such as the Royal Musical Association, the International Association of Music Libraries, the Internationale Stiftung Mozarteum, and RISM.
Scope and Content Note
The bulk of the collection consists of 246 published musicological writings, most of which are in the form of offprints of journal articles. Many of these were accompanied by correspondence that was removed to form a separate series. The collection also includes 9 complete journal issues that were not identified as being from a single author. The collection contains an assortment of booklets, including membership lists, organizational histories, and conference programs, from sixteen institutions. There are eighteen exhibition catalogs in the collection and sixteen catalogs from publishers and booksellers. Also, there are approximately eighty concert programs from various organizations from the years 1949-1998.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in nine series:
I. Published writings by King and others
II. Correspondence
III. Complete journal issues
IV. Institutional documents
V. Exhibition catalogs
VI. Vendor catalogs
VII. Programs
VIII. Papers related to King's Some British Collectors of Music
IX. Monographic titles collected by King
Container List
- Published writings by King and others, 1892-1993, I; Folder 1-246
  Chiefly offprints of musicological articles, with a few monographs and typescripts.
  Arranged alphabetically by author and then by title.
  - Abraham, Gerald Delius and the ethos of art nouveau, 1980., Published in Art nouveau, Jugendstil und Musik / herausgegeben aus Anlass des 80. Geburtstages von Willi Schuh von Jürg Stenzl. (Box 1, Folder 001)
  - Albrecht, Otto E. Musical treasures in the Morgan Library, 1972., Published in Notes, v. 28, no. 4 (June 1972) (Box 1, Folder 002)
  - American Library Association. Music: entry and heading, 1941., Published in A.L.A. Catalog Rules, preliminary second American edition. (Box 1, Folder 003)
  - Anderson, Emily, 1891-1962 Beethoven letters in the Royal College of Music, 1958., Published in RCM Magazine, v. 54, no. 2 (Summer 1958) Complete issue; King indicates on cover that Anderson gave him the copy Feb. 24, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 004)
  - Anderson, Emily, 1891-1962 Charles Neate: a Beethoven friendship, 1963., Published in Festschrift Otto Erich Deutsch zum 80. Geburtstag am 5. September 1963. Hrsg. von Walter Gerstenberg, Jan LaRue und Wolfgang Rehm. (Box 1, Folder 005)
  - Anderson, Emily, 1891-1962 The Letters of Beethoven: the necessity for a textually accurate edition, 1952., Published in Notes, v. 9, no. 4 (September 1952) (Box 1, Folder 006)
  - Bell, H. Idris (Harold Idris), Sir, b. 1879 Robert Ernest William Flower 1881-1946, 1948., Published in Proceedings of the British Academy, v. 32 (1948) (Box 1, Folder 007)
  - Bengtsson, Ingmar and Ruben Danielson. Handstilar och Notpikturer I Kungl. Musikaliska Akademiens Roman-Samling, 1955., Published in Studia Musicologica Upsaliensias Translated title: Handwriting and calligraphy in the J. H. Roman collection of the Swedish Royal Academy of Music (Box 1, Folder 008)
  - Benton, Rita Pleyel as music publisher, 1979., Published in Journal of the Musicological Society, v. 32, number 1 (1979) (Box 1, Folder 009)
  - Besterman, Theodore, 1904-1976 Art in the age of reason, 1972., Published in Studies on Voltaire and the eighteenth century, v. 87 (1972) With clipping about his widow's inheritance (Box 1, Folder 010)
  - Blume, Friedrich, 1893-1975 Hanslick, Eduard, 1956., Published in Sonderdruck aus Die Musik in Geschichte und Gegenwart Dictionary article (Box 1, Folder 011)
  - Boetticher, Wolfgang Georg Friedrich Händels caecilianische Kompositionen und die Tradition, 1970., Published in 50 Jahre Göttinger Handel-Festspiele Göttinger Handeltage 1968 (Box 1, Folder 012)
  - Boetticher, Wolfgang Weitere Beiträge zur Lasso-Forschung, 1969., Published in Renaissance-Muziek 1400-1600: Donum natalicium Rene Bernard Lenaerts (Box 1, Folder 013)
  - Boyden, David D. (David Dodge), 1910-1986 Case of the missing (violin) tutor; or, sleuthing in the 18th century, 1960., Given for the Music Conference of Faculty and Graduate Students of the University of California, Berkeley, March 15, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 014)
  - Boyden, David D. (David Dodge), 1910-1986 Geminiani and the first violin tutor, 1959., Published in Acta musicologica (1959) (Box 1, Folder 015)
  - Boyden, David D. (David Dodge), 1910-1986 Postscript to 'Geminiani and the first violin tutor', 1960., Published in Acta musicologica With letter of thanks to AHK (Box 1, Folder 016)
  - British Broadcasting Corporation. Sir Henry Wood: fifty years of the Proms, 1944., Compiled by Ralph Hill and C.B. Rees (Box 1, Folder 017)
  - British Museum. Dept. of Manuscripts. Catalogue of the musical manuscripts deposited on loan in the British Museum by the Royal Philharmonic Society of London, 1914., Includes autograph annotations, corrections, and an addenda. (Box 1, Folder 018)
  - Brockhoff, Maria Elisabeth Kirchenmusik im dem zu Paderborn im 17. Jahrhundert, 1967., Published in Kirchenmusikalisches Jahrbuch (1967) (Box 1, Folder 019)
  - Brook, Barry S. Fakaerti incognito symphonist or cutting down the Anhang, 1955., Published in Fontes Artis Musicae, v. 2, no. 2 (December 1955) (Box 1, Folder 020)
  - Brown, Maurice John Edwin Haydn, Mozart and Schubert in English Musicology, 1968., Published in Österreich und die angelsachsiche Welt: Kulturbegnungen und Vergleiche With letter from Brown to King. (Box 1, Folder 021)
  - Chrysander, Friedrich, 1826-1901 Bestand der Königlichen Privatmusik und Kirchenkapelle in London von 1710 bis 1755, 1892., Published in Vierteljahrsschr. für MusikWissenschaftliche, Heft 4 (1892) (Box 1, Folder 022)
  - Collegium Musicum "Audi et Tace". Important collection of 18th century orchestral material from the Archives of Collegium Musicum "Audi et Tace" Leeuwarden, 196-. (Box 1, Folder 023)
  - Cooper, Martin, 1910-1986 Which are the right notes?, 1957., Published in Daily Telegraph, March 30, 1957 Review of, and originally with Walter Emery's Editions and musicians: a survey of the duties of practical musicians & editions (removed to the general collection) (Box 1, Folder 024)
  - Crane, Frederick Bibliography of the iconography of music, 1971., Photocopy (Box 1, Folder 025)
  - Crichton, Ronald Glyndebourne 1934-1984, 1984., Published in Christie's International Magazine (July-August 1984) Complete issue (Box 1, Folder 026)
  - Croll, Gerhard Derra de Moroda Dance Archives, 1978., Published in Österreichische musik Zeitschrift, Jahrgang 33 (1978) Complete issue, with two other articles by Croll (Box 1, Folder 027)
  - Danmarks institut for international udveksling af videnskabelige publikationer. Musique danois: tirage a part de Dania polyglotta 1901-1944, III, 1949., Published in Dania polyglotta 1901-1944, Part III Edited by K. Schmidt-Phiseldeck, with collaboration of Henning Einersen (Box 1, Folder 028)
  - Dardo, Gianluigi Felice Anerio e la 'Congregazione dell’Oratorio', 1964., Published in Chigiana, v. 21 (1964) (Box 1, Folder 029)
  - Dart, Thurston, 1921-1971 History of Mayden-Musicke, 1961., Published in Bulletin of the New York Public Library (April 1961) (Box 1, Folder 030)
  - Davidsson, ¥ke, 1913- Collection of Italian manuscript music in the University Library of Uppsala, 1970., Published in Anales academiae regiae scientiarum upsaliensis (April 1970) (Box 1, Folder 031)
  - Derra de Moroda, Friderica, 1897-1978 Tanzschrift des 18. Jahrhunderts, 1967., Published in Maske und Kothurn, Jahrgang 13, Heft 1 (1967) (Box 1, Folder 032)
  - Deutsch, Otto Erich, 1883-1967 Freihaus-Theater auf der Wieden: zur feier seiner Eröffnung vor 150 Jahren (14. Oktober 1787), 1937., Published in Mitteilungen des Vereines für Geschichte der Stadt Wien, Band 16, 1937 "Scarce" (Box 1, Folder 033)
  - Deutsch, Otto Erich, 1883-1967 Nachruf für Paul Hirsch, 1951?., Published in Musik-Forschung, Jahrgang 5, Heft 2/3 (Box 1, Folder 034)
  - Dickinson, A. E. F. (Alan Edgar Frederic) Shakespeare in music, 1964., Published in Durham University Journal (March 1964) With concert program (Box 1, Folder 035)
  - Draudius, Georg, 1573-1635 Verzeichnisse deutscher musikalischer Bücher 1611 und 1625 / in originalgetreuem Nachdruck herausgegeben von Konrad Ameln., 1957., Inscription by King on prefatory page describing how he received this copy. (Box 1, Folder 036)
  - Elgar, Edward, 1857-1934 Falstaff: analytical essay by the composer, 1913., Published in Musical Times, Sept. 1913 (Box 1, Folder 037)
  - Elvers, Rudolf, 1924- Verzeichnis der Musik-Autographen von Fanny Hensel im Mendelssohn-Archiv zu Berlin, 1972., Published in Mendelssohn Studien, Band 1 (Box 1, Folder 038)
  - Elvers, Rudolf, 1934- Verzeichnis der von Felix Mendelssohn Bartholdy herausgegeben Werke Johann Sebastian Bachs, 1960., Published in Festschrift für Vizeprasident Professor D. Dr. Oskar Sohngen zum 60. Geburtstag am 5. Dezember 1960 (Box 1, Folder 039)
  - Farmer, Henry George, 1882-1965 Abdalqadir ibn Gaibi on instruments of music, 1962., Published in Oriens, v. 15 (1962) (Box 2, Folder 040)
  - Farmer, Henry George, 1882-1965 Some Oriental musical instruments at Kelvingrove, 1961., Published in Scottish Art Review, v. 8, no. 1 (1961) Entire issue (Box 2, Folder 041)
  - Farmer, Henry George, 1882-1965 Tenth century Arabic books on music, 1961., Published in Annual of Leeds University Oriental Society, v. 2 (1959-1961) (Box 2, Folder 042)
  - Feder, Georg Eine Haydn-Skizze in Ostiglia, 1961., Published in Analecta Band 12 (Box 2, Folder 043)
  - Federhofer, Renate Der Briefwechsel von Wilhelm Joseph von Wasielewski (1822-1896) in seiner Bedeutung für die Schumann-Forschung, 1974., Published in Convivium Musicorum: Festschrift Wolfgang Boetticher (Box 2, Folder 044)
  - Fédoroff, Yvette Code international de catalogage de la musique. V. 2: Code restreint = Limited code, 1961. (Box 2, Folder 045)
  - Fedorov, Vladimir, 1901-1979 Repertoire international des sources musicales, 1961., Published in Bulletin des Bibliotheques de France, v. 6, no. 1 (Jan. 1961) (Box 2, Folder 046)
  - Fellinger, Imogen Brahms zur Edition Chopinscher Klavierwerke, 1973., Published in Musicae Scientiae Collectanea: Festschrift Karl Gustav Fellerer (Box 2, Folder 047)
  - Fellinger, Imogen Brahms-Bild der Allgemeinen musikalischen Zeitung (1863 bis 1882), 1965., Published in Beitrage zur Geschichte der Musikkritik (1965) (Box 2, Folder 048)
  - Finscher, Ludwig Zum Begriff der Klassik in der Musik, 1966., Published in Deutsches Jahrbuch der Musikwissenschaft, Jahrgang 11 (1967) (Box 2, Folder 049)
  - Finscher, Ludwig Zum Parodieproblem bei Bach, 1969., Published in Bach-Interpretationen, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 050)
  - Fischer, Kurt von, 1913-2003 Erzieherische Aufgabe der Musik, 1960., Published in Neue Zürcher Zeitung, Sonntag, no. 3845 (November 6, 1960) (Box 2, Folder 051)
  - Flasdieck, Hermann Martin, 1900- Elisab. Faburden ‘Fauxbourdon’ und ne. Burden ’refrain’, 1956., Published in Anglia, Zeitschrift für englische Philogie, Band 74 (1956) (Box 2, Folder 052)
  - Fog, Dan Danische Musikverlage und notendruckereien, 1972. (Box 2, Folder 053)
  - Foreman, R. L. E. Bibliography of writings on Arnold Bax, 1970., Published in Current musicology, no. 10, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 054)
  - Fraenkel, Gottfried Samuel, 1901- Berlioz, the princess and Les Troyens, 1963., Published in Music & Letters, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 055)
  - Francis, Frank Chalton, Sir, 1901-1988 Catalogues of the British Museum, 1948., Published in Journal of documentation, v. 4, no. 1 (June 1948) (Box 2, Folder 056)
  - Friedrich, Heinz, 1922- Musik und Humanität, 1973., Published in Festvortrag zum funfzigjahrigen Jubilaum des Barenreiter-Verlags Kassel, 1. November 1973 (Box 2, Folder 057)
  - Gable, Frederick Kent Annotated catalog of rare musical items in the libraries of the University of Iowa, 1963., With program from Music Library Association meeting, January 1963, signed by Rita Benton (Box 2, Folder 058)
  - Geiringer, Karl, 1899-1989 Symbolism in the music of Bach, a lecture given at the Library of Congress, 23 May 1955, 1955. (Box 2, Folder 059)
  - Giegling, Franz, 1921- Über die Entwicklung des Notendrucks, 1954., Published in Stultifera Navis, Jahrgang 11, no. 3/4 (October 1954) (Box 2, Folder 060)
  - Gleich, Clemens von Bedeutung der Allgemeinen musikalische Zeitung 1798-1848 und 1863-1882, 1969. (Box 2, Folder 061)
  - Grasberger, Franz Autoren Katalog der Musikdrucke, 1957., Published in Code International de Catalogage de la musique, v. 1 (Box 2, Folder 062)
  - Grasberger, Franz Music department of the Austrian National Library, 1972. (Box 2, Folder 063)
  - Great Britain. Public Records Office. Guide to the Public Records. Part I: Introductory, 1949., With review by S.S. Wilson (London Times, Oct. 15, 1963) and pamphlet titled Information for readers, by S.S. Wilson, Dec. 1961 (Box 2, Folder 064)
  - Greer, David Clive, 1937- Manuscript additions in early printed music, 1991., Published in Music & Letters, v. 72 (1991) (Box 2, Folder 065)
  - Greg, W. W. (Walter Wilson), 1875-1959 Ronald Brunlees McKerrow 1872-1940, 1940?., Published in Proceedings of the British Academy, v. 26 (Box 2, Folder 066)
  - Grosvenor Library. Transportation in American popular songs: a bibliography of items in the Grosvenor Library, 1945., Published in Grosvenor Library Bulletin, v. 27, no. 3 (June 1945) (Box 2, Folder 067)
  - Hall, James S. Emergencies at sea: a review of 845 cases treated in the Downs, the North Sea and the English Channel, 1959., Published in Lancet (June 20 1959) (Box 2, Folder 068)
  - Hall, James S. Mr. Handel-his health!, 1960., Published in St. Mary's Hospital Gazzette, v. 66, no. 3 (April/May 1960)> Complete issue (Box 2, Folder 069)
  - Halm, Hans, 1887-1975 Schicksale der Bayerischen Staatsbibliothek während des zweiten Weltkriegs, 1949., Given to King, 1955. Includes obituary for Halm written by King (Box 2, Folder 070)
  - Hamilton, Iain, 1922-2000 Vienna opera and the 'Musikant' tradition, 1957., Published in Listener, 9 May 1957 (Box 2, Folder 071)
  - Harrison, Frank Ll. (Frank Llewellyn) and Joan Harrison, 1905-1987 Spanish elements in the music of two Maya groups in Chiapas, 1968., Published in Selected Reports, v. 1, no. 2 (1968) Written with Joan Harrison (Box 2, Folder 072)
  - Haydon, Glen, 1896-1966 Alfred Day and the theory of harmony, 1939., Paper read at International Congress of Musicology. September 11-16, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 073)
  - Haydon, Glen, 1896-1966 Hymns of Costanzo Festa: a style study, 1959., Published in Journal of the American Musicological Society, v. 12, number 2-3 (1959) (Box 3, Folder 074)
  - Haydon, Glen, 1896-1966 Music and philosophy, 1945., Published in Proceedings of the Royal Musical Association, session 71 (May 17 1945) (Box 3, Folder 075)
  - Haydon, Glen, 1896-1966 On the meaning of music, 1947., Lecture given at Library of Congress, 28 November, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 076)
  - Haydon, Glen, 1896-1966 On the problem of expression in baroque music, 1950., Published in Journal of the American Musicological Society, v. 3, no. 2 (Summer 1950) (Box 3, Folder 077)
  - Haywood, Charles, 1904- George Bernard Shaw on incidental music in the Shakespearian theater, 1969., Published in Shakespeare Jahrbuch, Band 105 (1969) (Box 3, Folder 078)
  - Heartz, Daniel Au pres de vous: Claudin’s chanson and the commerce of publishers' arrangements, 1971., Published in Journal of the American Musicological Society, v. 24, no. 2 (1971) With letter from Heartz (Box 3, Folder 079)
  - Hill, Richard S. (Richard Synyer), 1901-1961 Collecting American sheet music, 1947., Published in Publishers' weekly, v. 152, no. 22 (Nov. 29, 1947) Complete issue (Box 3, Folder 080)
  - Hill, Richard S. (Richard Synyer), 1901-1961 Melody of the Star Spangled Banner in the United States before 1820, 1951., Published in Essays honoring Lawrence C. Wroth With correpondence (Box 3, Folder 081)
  - Hilmar, Ernst Erganzungen zu Emil Vogels 'Bibliothek der Gedruckten weltlichen vocalmusik italiens, aus den Jahrhen 1500-1700', 1967., Published in Studien zur italienisch-deutschen Musikgeschichte, Band 114 (1967) (Box 3, Folder 082)
  - Hirsch, Paul, 1881-1951 Contemporary English editions of Beethoven, 1953., Published in Music Review, v. 14, no. 1 (Feb. 1953) Written with C. B. Oldman (Box 3, Folder 083)
  - Hirsch, Paul, 1881-1951 Dr. Arnold's Handel edition (1787-1797), 1947., Published in Music Review (May 1947) (Box 3, Folder 084)
  - Hirsch, Paul, 1881-1951 Some early Mozart editions, 1940., Published in Music Review, v. 1, no. 1 (Feb. 1940) (Box 3, Folder 085)
  - Hoboken, Anthony van, 1887-1983 Archiv fÜr Photoprogramme: musikalischer Meisterhandschriften in der Musiksammlung der österreichischen Nationalbibliothek in Wien, 1958., Includes invitation to 90th birthday celebration for Hoboken, March 23, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 086)
  - Holland, Jeanette B. Sharp manuscript, London 1759-c1793: a uniquely annotated music catalogue, 1969., Published in Bulletin of the New York Public Library, v. 73, no. 3 (March 1969) Written with Jan LaRue (Box 3, Folder 087)
  - Hopkinson, Cecil Berlioz and the 'Marseillaise', 1970., Published in Music & Letters, v. 51, no. 4 (October 1970) With letter from Hopkinson, 1970. (Box 3, Folder 088)
  - Hopkinson, Cecil Fundamentals of music bibliography, 1955., Published in Journal of documentation, v. 11, no. 3 (Sept. 1955) (Box 3, Folder 089)
  - Hopkinson, Cecil Histories of French music publishers connected with Hector Berlioz, 1951., Published in Bibliography of Hector Berlioz "One of twenty-five copies printed" (Box 3, Folder 090)
  - Hopkinson, Cecil Towards a definition of certain terms in music bibliography, 1959., Published in Music, libraries and instruments (Box 3, Folder 091)
  - Le Huray, Peter Towards a definitive study of pre-restoration Anglican service music, 1960., Published in Musica disciplina, v. 14 (1960) (Box 3, Folder 092)
  - International Association of Music Libraries. Ländergruppe der Deutschen Demokratischen Republik. Regeln für die alphabetische Katalogisierung der Musikalien, 1962. (Box 3, Folder 093)
  - International Chopin Foundation. Chopin's letters to Delfina, 1961., Published in Bulletin of the International Chopin Foundation, v. 3 (November 1961) (Box 3, Folder 094)
  - International Chopin Foundation. Chopin's letters to the Countess Delfina Potocka, 1961., Published in Bulletin of the International Chopin Foundation, v. 3 (October 1961) Appendix to the paper read at the panel discussion organized on September 14, 1961, in New York, bu the International Chopin Foundation, Inc., ---. Text by Matteo Glinski. (Box 3, Folder 095)
  - International Chopin Foundation. Controversy over Chopin's letters to Delfina definitively closed in Poland, 1969., Published in Bulletin of the International Chopin Foundation, v. 9 (Winter 1969) (Box 3, Folder 096)
  - Jacobi, Erwin R. (Erwin Reuben), 1909-1979 Augustus Frederic Christopher Kollman als Theoretiker, 1956., Published in Archiv für Musikwissenschaft, Jahrgang 30 (1956) Includes typewritten leaf of corrections. (Box 3, Folder 097)
  - Jacobi, Erwin R. (Erwin Reuben), 1909-1979 Die Entwicklung der Musiktheorie in England nach der Zeit von Jean-Philippe Rameau, 1957. (Box 3, Folder 098)
  - Jacobi, Erwin R. (Erwin Reuben), 1909-1979 Harmonic theory in England after the time of Rameau, 1957., Published in Journal of music theory, v.1, no. 2 (November 1957) (Box 3, Folder 099)
  - Jacobi, Erwin R. (Erwin Reuben), 1909-1979 Jean-Adam Serre: ein vergessen Schweizer Musiktheoretiker, 1958., Published in Schweizerische Musikzeitung, April 1, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 100)
  - Jacobi, Erwin R. (Erwin Reuben), 1909-1979 Liste meiner Publikationen auf dem Gebiet der Musik, 1958., Copy of typescript (2 leaves) (Box 3, Folder 101)
  - Jacobi, Erwin R. (Erwin Reuben), 1909-1979 Über die Angleichung nachschlagender Sechzehntel an Triolen: Bemerkungen und Hinweise zum gleichnamigen Artikel von Eta Harich-Schneider, 1960., Published in Musik-Forschung, Jahrgang 13, Haft 3 (1960) (Box 3, Folder 102)
  - Jacobi, Erwin R. (Erwin Reuben), 1909-1979 Veröffentlichungen auf dem Gebiet der Musik, Oktober 1968, 1968., Copy of typescript (11 leaves) (Box 3, Folder 103)
  - Jacquot, Jean Luth et sa musique, 1958., Published in Acta musicologica (1958) (Box 3, Folder 104)
  - Johansson, Cari Studier Kring Patrik Alströmers musiksamlung, 1961., Published in Svensk tidskrift för musikforskning (Box 3, Folder 105)
  - Jong, W. C. de Handel's 'Alexander's Feast', 1968., Published in Mens en melodie, Jahrgang 23, no. 8 (August 1968) (Box 3, Folder 106)
  - Kallmann, Helmut Music division of the National Library: the first five years, 1975., Published in Canada Music Book, v. 10 (Spring/Summer 1975) (Box 3, Folder 107)
  - Kassler, Jamie Croy Music made easy to infant capacity,1714-1830: some facets of British music education, 1976., Published in Studies in Music (1976) (Box 3, Folder 108)
  - Kecskeméti, István, 1920-1999 Sussmayr-Handschriften der Nationalbibliothek Szechenyi in Budapest, 1961., Published in Mozart-Jahrbuch (1959) (Box 3, Folder 109)
  - Kerslake, John F. Collecting Handel, 1986., Published in Antique collector (February 1986) (Box 3, Folder 110)
  - King, A. Hyatt (Alec Hyatt), 1911-1994 British books on music, 1960-1970: an exhibition of books & periodicals arranged by the British Council, 1970., Accompanied by King's essay of same title. (Box 3, Folder 111)
  - King, A. Hyatt (Alec Hyatt), 1911-1994 Das Neue Kochel-Verzeichnis, 1965., Published in Musik-Forschung, Jahrgang 18, Heft 3 (1965) 2 copies (Box 3, Folder 112)
  - King, A. Hyatt (Alec Hyatt), 1911-1994 Philipp Karl Hoffmann: his cadenzas to some of Mozart's piano concertos and elaborations of their slow movements, 1959., 3 copies (Box 3, Folder 113)
  - King, A. Hyatt (Alec Hyatt), 1911-1994 Study of music in British universities, 1951., Published in Year's work in music, 1950-51 Complete issue; includes King's other article, Bibliography of published music and musical literature. (Box 3, Folder 114)